const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which neurotransmitter is secreted by the Raphe nuclei that also plays a role in non-REM sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the midbrain?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen of Monro","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 30-year-old man reported to the emergency department with a complaint of a dog bite on the right arm. The casualty is conscious but the wound is bleeding. No previous medical or surgical history is reported. After history taking, what is the first step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Testing the dog for rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of IV saline","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of anti-rabies vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Washing and debridement of the wound","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which neurotransmitter is most commonly released by pre-ganglionic sympathetic neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following cavities is present in the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Third ventricle","bool":true},{"option":"Fourth ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral aqueduct","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which one of the following is not a dural fold?","answers":[{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragma sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Falx cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Hypophysis cerebri","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which types of cells are not present in the cerebellar cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Granule cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate cells","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basket cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal cells","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is an indolamine derived from tryptophan?","answers":[{"option":"Leukotriene","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Chitin","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandin","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"REM sleep is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"High voltage, low frequency EEG activity","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid conjugate movements of the eye balls","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha waves of EEG","bool":false},{"option":"70% - 80% of the total sleeping period","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of dreams","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following sensations are spared in anterior cord syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Vibration, crude touch, and pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Crude touch and two point discrimination","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception, two point discrimination, and vibration","bool":true},{"option":"Pain and temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Fine touch and pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What does a 'cobweb' appearance of the CSF indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pyogenic meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 34-year-old man complains of hemisensory loss and hemiparesis of the leg and foot of the contralateral side of the body. He also has difficulty in identifying objects and has developed personality changes. His MRI shows a compromised area with reduced blood supply. Which artery is responsible for these losses?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following brain structures is responsible for emotional memory?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":true},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Gliosis is a process in which there is hyperplasia or hypertrophy of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Myelin sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"In neonates, what causes acute pyogenic meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Toxoplasma gondii","bool":false},{"option":"Necator americanus","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following organisms causes chronic bacterial meningoencephalitis?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"L-DOPA is converted to dopamine by which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"DOPA decarboxylase","bool":true},{"option":"DOPA carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA reductase","bool":false},{"option":"DOPA oxidase","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which one of the following forms the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Damage to which part of the brain results in a condition called athetosis?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which structure is present deep in the lateral sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary motor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Primary sensory cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Supplementary motor area","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the essential amino acids is used to synthesize L-DOPA?","answers":[{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":true},{"option":"Linoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Linolenic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following sensations is detected by nociceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Taste","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Vibration","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The nerve endings at the end of the receptor have a receptor potential due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Change in potential","bool":true},{"option":"Adaptation","bool":false},{"option":"Excitatory post synaptic potential","bool":false},{"option":"End plate potential","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Damage to which of the following results in the loss of pain sensation?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Light touch sensations are lost when which of the following is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column medial lemniscus pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Cuneocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following key enzymes is required for the synthesis of acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Choline acyltransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl cholineaminase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acetylsynthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline synthetase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acetyltransferase","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which structure does not pass through the foramen magnum of the skull?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal root of XI cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Dura mater","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral veins","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior spinal arteries","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is the first choice of modality for diagnosing and examining suspected spinal cord lesions in patients who have suffered trauma?","answers":[{"option":"Positron emission tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Electroencephalography","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient is suffering from wakefulness and narcolepsy. Which one of the following is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Reticular formation","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebelllum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which one of the following innervates intrafusal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Both alpha and gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"B fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Unmyelinated fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which one of the fibers are used by sensory receptors to carry impulse from the periphery to the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Efferent fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Preganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Free nerve endings","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic","bool":false},{"option":"Afferent fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for fine hand movements?","answers":[{"option":"Premotor cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory association centre","bool":false},{"option":"Primary motor cortex","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What enzyme degrades acetylcholine?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Thioesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Endoribonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Pectinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholinesterase","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Lesion of which of the following would cause loss of vibration in the upper limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal white column on left side","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white column on right side","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white columns on both sides","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 21-year-old male got into an accident after which he could not move his body, except for the head, and the weak shrugging of the shoulders. He also lost all senses below the neck level. At which of the following levels is the lesion most likely to have occurred?","answers":[{"option":"Below T3","bool":false},{"option":"Below C7","bool":false},{"option":"Below T1","bool":false},{"option":"Below L1","bool":false},{"option":"Below C3","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following pairs of muscles is involved in shrugging of the shoulders and the movement of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezius and platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius and levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Scalene and platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and longus capitus","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid and trapezius","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"In complete cord transection at the cervical level, what would be observed on checking for reflexes of the limbs?","answers":[{"option":"Absent reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Initial hyporeflexia followed by hyperreflexia","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Exaggerated reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Normal reflexes","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 21-year-old male got into an accident and is unable to move his body, except for the weak shrugging of his shoulders and the movement of his head. Which of the following nerves must be intact to allow this movement of the shoulders?","answers":[{"option":"Infrascapular nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprascpular nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What would be observed in complete cord transection at the cervical level?","answers":[{"option":"Hemiplegia of right side","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiplegia of left side","bool":false},{"option":"Monoplegia of right upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Paraplagia","bool":false},{"option":"Tetraplegia","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Damage to which of the following nerves is responsible for the labored breathing in a patient with complete cord transection at cervical level?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person had an accident after which he is unable to move his body, except for his head, and the weak shrugging of the shoulders. He has also lost all his senses including light touch, pain, and temperature senses below the neck level, and is now unable to perceive his position in space. The doctor immediately provides him with ventilation as he was not able to breathe properly. Which of the following is suspected?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Brown-Sequard syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Complete cord transection syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Central cord syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Poliomyelitis","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for carrying vibratory and proprioceptive information from the lower parts of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Rubrospinal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior white column","bool":true},{"option":"Spinotectal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person has lost sense of vibration, proprioception, and discriminative touch on the right upper limb. Lesion of which of the following is responsible for this loss?","answers":[{"option":"Medial lemniscus","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus","bool":true},{"option":"Left fasciculus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Left fasciculus cuneatus","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus gracilis","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Slow-wave sleep is concerned with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in peripheral vascular tone","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in respiratory sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Dreams with less muscle involvement","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in basal metabolic rate","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following waves are seen when a person is awake and is alert?","answers":[{"option":"Theta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Delta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha waves","bool":false},{"option":"Low voltage spindles","bool":false},{"option":"Beta waves","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following terms is used for fibers that connect different regions in the same cerebral hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricles","bool":false},{"option":"Association fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"Projection fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Commissural fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following arteries provides collateral vascular supply to the macular region of the occipital lobe?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The corpora quadrigemina is a region present on the posterior surface of the midbrain. Which part of it is involved in the visual pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Medial geniculate nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Association fibers are the nerve fibers that connect different regions within the same hemisphere. Which of the following is categorized as the association fiber?","answers":[{"option":"External capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulum","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following cells secrete nerve growth factors?","answers":[{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following structures forms the medial wall of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral margin of the thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following would not be affected by a fracture involving the posterior cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous part of the temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Petrous part of the temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid part of the temporal bone","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The consensual light reflex that leads to the constriction of the pupil of the eye with reference to light falling on the opposite eye is mediated via which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampal commissure","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following substances is responsible for the inhibition of the satiety center and activation of the hunger center?","answers":[{"option":"Leptin","bool":false},{"option":"Ghrelin","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha melanocyte stimulation hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is a contraindication of a thrombolytic drug?","answers":[{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"History of hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pulmonary thromboembolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Acute ischemic stroke","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient is given an opioid injection after surgery for pain relief. Which of the following statements is correct regarding opioids?","answers":[{"option":"They are local anesthetic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Giving NSAIDs in addition will help provide more relief","bool":true},{"option":"Their action will be enhanced by naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"They will cause placebo effect","bool":false},{"option":"They will cause more respiratory stimulation","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following would most likely be affected in the thalamic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Inferolateral aspect of thalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior aspect of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterosuperior thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior portion of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroinferior portion of the thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The pineal gland is associated with which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following accurately describes the function of the nuclear bag fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Relaxation of muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of antagonistic muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Sense the sustained pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Maintaining muscle length","bool":false},{"option":"Sense the onset of stress","bool":true}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient presents to the clinic with a degenerative bone disease that is causing narrowing of the foramen magnum. Which of the following structures would not be affected by the above condition?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior and anterior spinal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory spinal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following substances will be seen in nissl substance under the microscope?","answers":[{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi complex","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The red nucleus gives rise to the rubrospinal tract that arises from which of the following parts?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following forms the floor of the anterior horn of the lateral ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Genu of the corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the caudate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Head of the caudate","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior column of the fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is important for the perception of pain in the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Clark's nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus proprius","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferent nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia gelatinosa","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus dorsalis","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient is admitted to the emergency department due to a sudden feeling of nausea and vomiting. On analysis, gait and posture are normal but right foot movement is impaired. Which of the following parts must be involved in the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis","bool":false},{"option":"Right cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Left cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate zone","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following tracts carries the sensation of crude touch?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral spinothalamic pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Spinoreticular tract","bool":false},{"option":"Extrapyramidal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal white column","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal pathway","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following pathways is responsible for the transmission of senses of discriminative or fine touch?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal column-medial lemniscus pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Spinoreticular pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Spinotectal pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Anesthesia was given to the patient in order not to feel the pain during surgery. How does the anesthesia work?","answers":[{"option":"Blockage of voltage gated sodium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand gated sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of voltage gated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand gated potassium channels","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The limbic system is the body's most important system regarding emotions and behavior, which part of the limbic system is responsible for memory consolidation?","answers":[{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true},{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Reward and punishment centers are located in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Limbic system","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Somatosensory area-I is highly localized and the somatosensory area-II is poorly localized. An ablation of the somatosensory area-I will significantly impair which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pain perception","bool":false},{"option":"Crude touch","bool":false},{"option":"Proprioception","bool":false},{"option":"Ability to judge shapes and forms of the objects","bool":true},{"option":"Vibration","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"At which of the following structures do the nerve impulses converge to create an action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Axon","bool":false},{"option":"Axon hillock","bool":true},{"option":"Synaptic junction","bool":false},{"option":"Dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axolemma","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following represents the type of memory that is acquired but becomes unconscious and automatic later on?","answers":[{"option":"Non-associative learning","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic memory","bool":false},{"option":"Procedural memory","bool":true},{"option":"Associative learning","bool":false},{"option":"Priming","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following terms accurately describes the condition in which a person is unable to read?","answers":[{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false},{"option":"Prosopagnosia","bool":false},{"option":"Alexia","bool":true},{"option":"Aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Lesion of which of the following parts will result in global aphasia?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Wernicke's and Broca's area","bool":true},{"option":"Association area","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area-I","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the negative resting membrane potential of -70 millivolts of neurons?","answers":[{"option":"Leaky sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Voltage gated potassium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Leaky potassium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Voltage gated sodium channels","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"To which of the following classes do the endorphins belong?","answers":[{"option":"Peptide","bool":true},{"option":"Amine","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Catecholamines","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is associated with increased dopamine levels?","answers":[{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Global aphasia without hemiparesis","bool":false},{"option":"Agnosia","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is not derived from tyrosine?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient presents to the clinic with dementia and involuntary jerking movements of the body. On examination, it is found that the GABA secreting neurons of caudate and putamen are damaged. Which of the following is the most probable condition from which the patient must be suffering?","answers":[{"option":"Athetosis","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Chorea","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Amino acid is converted to an amine by which of the following processes?","answers":[{"option":"Decarboxylation","bool":true},{"option":"Methylation","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydration","bool":false},{"option":"Deamination","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"By which of the following processes does the monoamine oxidase catalyzes the catecholamine catabolism?","answers":[{"option":"Deamination","bool":true},{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Methylation","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydrogenation","bool":false},{"option":"Decarboxylation","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"In which of the following phases would the ketone bodies be utilized?","answers":[{"option":"After meal","bool":false},{"option":"Fasting","bool":true},{"option":"Between meals","bool":false},{"option":"Well fed state","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemic phase","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What is the basic structure of the sphingosine?","answers":[{"option":"A 18-carbon amino alcohol with unsaturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":true},{"option":"A 18-carbon amino alcohol with saturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":false},{"option":"A 16-carbon amino alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"A 12-carbon alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"A 17-carbon amino alcohol with unsaturated hydrocarbon chain","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Assists accumulation of potentially hazardous chemicals inside CNS","bool":false},{"option":"It is found in peripheral nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents accumulation of potentially hazardous chemicals inside CNS","bool":true},{"option":"Endothelial cells are absent in this region","bool":false},{"option":"It is a freely permeable region","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is a common complication of cerebral amyloid angiopathy with hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Intracranial necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Intracerebral clotting","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral edema","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A public health officer ordered his staff to take measures for vector control in order to prevent diseases. Which of the following diseases can be prevented by this project?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Peptic ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Diphtheria","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Gastritis","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following should be the relationship between the doctor and the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Consumeristic relationship","bool":false},{"option":"Both should be equally involved in consultation as partners","bool":false},{"option":"Mutual relationship","bool":true},{"option":"Default relationship","bool":false},{"option":"Paternalistic relationship","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of stroke in young adults?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of exercise","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty diet","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is the best method to detect slipped intervertebral disc or herniated disc?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"Electroencephalography","bool":false},{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is an antagonist of the muscarinic receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Curare","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Atropine","bool":true},{"option":"Botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Muscarine","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is the first complete documented set of rules of ancient ethics?","answers":[{"option":"Nuremberg code","bool":false},{"option":"Alma mater","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocratic oath","bool":true},{"option":"Declaration of Geneva","bool":false},{"option":"Helsinki Declaration","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which part of the neuron has the Nissl substance?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Soma","bool":true},{"option":"Axon","bool":false},{"option":"Synaptic bouton","bool":false},{"option":"Axon hillock","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which nucleus is activated upon suckling during breastfeeding?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Supraoptic","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which part of the internal capsule is involved in a pure motor stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Sublentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":true},{"option":"Genu","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following nuclei is not present in the white matter of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Fastigial","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":true},{"option":"Dentate","bool":false},{"option":"Emboliform","bool":false},{"option":"Globose","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Acetylcholine increases the permeability of which of the following ions when it binds to nicotinic receptors at the postsynaptic neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Damage to which structure causes Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which artery is involved in the supply of leg and foot areas of the primary motor cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 58-year-old patient comes to the emergency room with his wife with complaints of inability to speak, weakness in his right upper limb, and is unable to understand what others are saying. The symptoms started 1 hour ago. He is known to have had hypertension for the past 8 years. A physical exam is performed by the doctor and a CT scan is ordered since the doctor suspects a stroke. Which artery is most likely to have the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cerebellar","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle cerebral","bool":false},{"option":"Left middle cerebral","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Hemiballismus is caused due to damage to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Caudate","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which cranial nerve nucleus extends throughout all three structures of the brainstem?","answers":[{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"If a transverse section is taken through the caudal part of the pons, at the level of the facial colliculus, which structure will remain unaffected?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Medial vestibular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What is the initial modality used for fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Myelography","bool":false},{"option":"PET","bool":false},{"option":"CT","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A reproductive age female reported to the outpatient department with no prior dose of tetanus vaccine. What are the recommended doses by EPI protocol of tetanus for long-term prevention?","answers":[{"option":"Two doses","bool":false},{"option":"Four doses","bool":false},{"option":"Three doses","bool":false},{"option":"Five doses","bool":true},{"option":"Single dose","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which structure is not present in the medial wall of the cerebral hemisphere?","answers":[{"option":"Cuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Precuneus","bool":false},{"option":"Insula","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person has social and emotional changes due to damage to which lobe?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral lobule","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following options is incorrectly matched?","answers":[{"option":"Multipolar Neurons – sensory and dorsal nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar neurons – special senses","bool":false},{"option":"Betz cell – motor activity","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo unipolar – dorsal root ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells – cerebellar cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Viral meningitis is detected by an increase in which of the following components of cerebrospinal fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Protein","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The choroid plexus of the third ventricle is derived from which part of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Alar plates of diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Roof plates of diencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Rathke’s pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate of prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Floor plate of diencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following does not arise from the neural tube?","answers":[{"option":"Neuroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Microglia","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"In chronic gliosis, elongated, brightly eosinophilic protein aggregates within astrocyte processes are formed. What are they termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Rosenthal fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Nissl bodies","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial granules","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrillary astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Obstruction at the foramen of Monro will cause which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Communicating hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Non communicating hydrocephalus","bool":true},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by all preganglionic neurons of autonomic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Substance P","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The visual cortex is present in the wall of which of the following sulci?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Central sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"Calcarine sulcus","bool":true},{"option":"Precentral sulcus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which fibrinolytic drug also has an antigenic effect?","answers":[{"option":"Urokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Urokinase + Alteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Alteplase","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Streptokinase + Alteplase","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about the glomerulus in the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Present in molecular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Mossy fibers synapse here","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi cells are present here","bool":false},{"option":"Present in granular layer","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The nerve which passes through stylomastoid foramen does not supply which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"An 8-year-old boy presented with sudden neck stiffness, headache, and flu-like symptoms. After three days, his CSF showed mild lymphocytic pleocytosis, slightly decreased glucose, and mildly increased protein. Which organism is likely responsible for this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Borrelia burgdorferi","bool":false},{"option":"Enterovirus","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which artery supplies the choroid plexus of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":true},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The arterial supply of the dorsal and lateral walls of the medulla oblongata is affected. Which of the following will not be observed?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sense of pain","bool":false},{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of sense of temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Dysphonia","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person has lost point discrimination on his left hand. Which structure is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus at the level of C2","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus cuneatus at the level of thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Left fasciculus gracilis at the level of C2","bool":false},{"option":"Right fasciculus gracilis at the level of thoracic vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Right medial lemniscus at the level of pons","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person has resting tremors, a stooping posture, and a shuffling gait. Which structure of the brain has undergone neuronal degeneration?","answers":[{"option":"Cortical areas","bool":false},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Basal nuclei","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Right hemisection of the spinal cord at the level of C8 will result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccid paralysis of left upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of lower face","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of right upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of left lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis of right lower limb","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"In increased thirst, the brain responds to the increased osmolality of the extracellular fluid by activating which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Ionic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Aquaporins","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptors","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The anterior cerebral artery will be compressed as a result of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Transtentorial herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Subfalcine herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellar herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Uncinate herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar herniation","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Epithalamus is a structure located on the posterior part of the diencephalon. Which of the following is not a part of the epithalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Glial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Pineal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":true},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What is the role of the corticospinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic system control","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic system control","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of voluntary movement","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary motor control","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex postural movement","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the dynamic control of muscle spindles?","answers":[{"option":"Nuclear bag fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Intrafusal fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma-s fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear chain fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Extrafusal fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Sense of vibration travels to the central nervous system through which of the following pathways?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient with right cerebellar dysfunction will most likely present with which of the following signs?","answers":[{"option":"Positive Romberg's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Swaying back and forth with eyes closed","bool":false},{"option":"Dysdiadochokinesia","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Person tends to fall to the left","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is a pathognomonic feature found in patients with rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrophobia","bool":true},{"option":"Convulsions","bool":false},{"option":"Agoraphobia","bool":false},{"option":"Irritation","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The highly vascular layer of the spinal cord forms which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Falx cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Filum terminale","bool":true},{"option":"Tentorium cerebelli","bool":false},{"option":"Cisterna magna","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which cranial nerve is concerned with accommodation and light reflex?","answers":[{"option":"III","bool":true},{"option":"V","bool":false},{"option":"IV","bool":false},{"option":"II","bool":false},{"option":"VI","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Pinpoint pupils are seen in hemorrhage of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Cerebrospinal-filled cavities are lined by ependymal cells. These cells are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pachymeninges","bool":false},{"option":"Leptomeninges","bool":false},{"option":"Meningovax","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroepithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Marginal Layer","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A 60-year-old diabetic patient has numbness in his left foot and leg. Which artery is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Left middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which structure controls the function of the motor cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Supplementary motor area","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Somatosensory area","bool":false},{"option":"Premotor area","bool":true}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A pathway that consists of the superior olivary nucleus and the trapezoid body connecting to the inferior colliculus and the medial geniculate body is responsible for detecting which sense?","answers":[{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Equilibrium","bool":false},{"option":"Vision","bool":false},{"option":"Gustation","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing","bool":true}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which trigeminal nerve nucleus senses touch and pressure from the face?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Motor nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Infections from the nasal mucosa can spread to the olfactory bulb in the cranial cavity due to the olfactory nerve passing through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Crista galli","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior perforated substance","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Cribriform plate","bool":true}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What is the combination of a motor nerve and all the muscle fibers it innervates called?","answers":[{"option":"Functional unit","bool":false},{"option":"Motor unit","bool":true},{"option":"Motor end plate","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromuscular junction","bool":false},{"option":"Synapse","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is a possible side effect of morphine?","answers":[{"option":"Mydriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Blood pressure elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Right supranuclear facial nerve damage will result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Right lower facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Left upper facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Right upper facial motor loss","bool":false},{"option":"Left lower facial motor loss","bool":true},{"option":"Upper and lower facial motor loss","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Nerves supplying extraocular muscles of the eye pass through which part of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolentiform","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior limb","bool":false},{"option":"Sublentiform","bool":false},{"option":"Genu","bool":true}]},{"id":145,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person stepped on a piece of glass and flexed his right leg to avoid it while his left leg extended. What is this called?","answers":[{"option":"Crossed extensor reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Galloping reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Withdrawal reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Reciprocal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"What is the function of the vestibulospinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitates flexor muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Reflex postural movement","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic control","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitates extensor muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Rapid, skilled voluntary movement","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A patient dies due to cerebellar tonsil herniation through the foramen magnum. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve compression","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory failure","bool":true},{"option":"Epidural hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":148,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"Which of the following is not associated with the fight and flight response?","answers":[{"option":"Paravertebral ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracolumbar outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Prevertebral ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Craniosacral outflow","bool":true},{"option":"Long postganglionic fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"A person suffered from a head injury resulting in the damage of the temporal lobe of the dominant hemisphere. The person is unable to understand words. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Expressive aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Alexia","bool":false},{"option":"Receptive aphasia","bool":true},{"option":"Global aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2021","question":"The myelin sheath in the central nervous system is made of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false}]}]
export default arr